

# KATRIN HOFSTETTER

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER



#### **SUMMARY**

Certified full-stack web developer with experience in (online) journalism, marketing, social media and teaching. Always motivated to improve her coding skills and gain new technology skills. Loves to learn languages (not only those remote from humans) and writing for large and small editorial offices, including tech-related magazines (E-Commerce).



#### **SKILLS**

#### Front-End

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, React, React Native, jQuery, (React) Bootstrap, Typescript, Angular, Angular Material

#### **Back-End**

NodeJS, RESTful APIs, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Heroku, AWS, Serverless



#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bootcamp Full-Stack Web Development

Career Foundry | June 2021 - now

- More than 200 days of training and mentoring with industry leading Front-End and Senior Full-Stack Web Developer
- Intensive project-based training program with a focus on JavaScript and most prominent libraries, frameworks and tools
- Built multiple projects from scratch using HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React and Angular



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Crossmedia Traineeship

Ebner Media Group/Internetworld.de | Sept. 2020

- Feb. 2021
  - Writing of online and print articles
  - Selecting suitable image material
  - Working with Content Management System InterRed
  - Editing articles of external authors
  - Compiling news for daily newsletters in the Salesforce Marketing Cloud
  - Social Media Marketing on business platforms such as LinkedIn and Xing

#### **Print Editorial Internship**

Münchner Merkur | Jan. 2020 - March 2020

- Conducting interviews
- Researching, writing, editing, and designing print and online articles
- Posting on social media (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram)

#### Online Editorial Internship

Lokale Stimme GmbH | June 2019 - August 2019

- Researching and writing online articles
- Conducting interviews and on-site reporting
- Editing and cutting of own photo and video material
- Working with Google Analytics and WordPress



# KATRIN HOFSTETTER

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER



#### **EXAMPLE PROJECTS**

- Chat App for mobile devices (Android and iOS) created with React Native.
   Able to send messages with text, images and location
- Serverless, Progressive Web
   Application (PWA) using React and
   the test-driven development
   approach (TDD). Connected with the
   Google Calendar API
- Client side for a movie web app, once with React and once with Angular, with routing, rich interactions and several interface views (based on existing server-side code (REST API and database)



## CONTACT



Ampfingstraße 17 81671 München



+49 176 / 3473 8658



katrin\_hofstetter@gmx.de



https://kittekat14.github.io/portfoliowebsite



https://www.linkedin.com/in/katrinhofstetter-25b945181/



https://github.com/Kittekat14



# **WORK EXPERIENCE (2)**

Trade fair hostess and promoter self-employed | Jan. 2019 - Jan. 2020

- Product presentation and explanation, inquiring about customer needs
- Greeting, assisting and informing customers
- Assigning appointments, forwarding interested parties to specialist personnel

# Traineeship as high school teacher

Gymnasium Donauwörth and Gabrieli-Gymnasium Eichstätt | Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Independent teaching (planning and implementation of individual lessons, units and sequences)
- Reflection on lessons taught
- Assessment and revision of students' work and oral student contributions
- Further training in subject-specific and general pedagogical seminars



#### **UNIVERSITY**

Staatsexamen Social Studies (Teacher Exam) Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München | October 2014 - March 2018

# Staatsexamen Latin and History (Teacher Exam)

Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München | October 2011 - September 2017



## LANGUAGES / OTHER

German - native speaker English - fluent French - advanced knowledge Italian - basic knowledge

Git Version Control, Agile & Kanban (Project Management), Test-Driven-Development, JSDoc, TypeDoc, Figma